Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, 1967-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, 1967-1993
Mus. Arc. 1.6
Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1941-1993
31 boxes (1165 audio cassettes)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains 249 cassettes featuring performances either by Mikhashoff or of his music, 801 non-commercial cassettes and 115 commercially-released cassettes that do not contain performances or works by Mikhashoff.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Yvar Mikhashoff, 1993.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternative Form Available
The first series of the collection was digitally reformatted in 2015. The funds for the reformatting were generously supplied by the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music.
The original recordings were made on cassettes. The contents were digitized onto a hard drive that is stored with the collection. Preservation wav files were created to match the original cassette sides. Production master files (wav) were created to match musical works or other segments of the contents and service copy files (mp3) were created from the production masters.
Biographical Note
Yvar-Emilian Mikhashoff was born Ronald MacKay in Troy near Albany, New York in 1941. He began piano studies with Betty Weir and Stanley Hummel in Albany. At the Eastman School of Music in 1959, he first took a major in composition and cello, then changed to piano studies with Armand Basile. In the 1961 academic year, he studied piano at the Juilliard School in New York City. He also had a career as a ballroom dancer from 1962-1965.
In 1964 Mikhashoff entered the University of Houston for studies in piano with Albert Hirsh. He earned a B.M. in 1967 and continued with graduate study in composition with Elmer Schoettle and obtained his M.M. in 1968. It was during this period that MacKay adopted his grandfather's name, Mikhashoff.
Receiving a Fulbright scholarship in 1968, he studied the music of the French Impressionists with Nadia Boulanger. After his return to the United States, Mikhashoff entered the University of Texas at Austin as a doctoral candidate in composition and studied with Hunter Johnson, Kent Kennan, Janet McGaughey and Karl Korte. He earned a Doctor of Musical Arts degree with a major in composition and a minor in literature in August 1973 and founded the Cambiata Soloists ensemble. In the fall of 1973 Mikhashoff was appointed Assistant Professor in the Music Department at the State University of New York at Buffalo. Based in Buffalo until his death in 1993, Mikhashoff had an international performing career which led him to promote new music and American music around the world.
Mikhashoff had a genius for programming, a talent he utilized extensively while organizing many festivals and broadcasts of new music throughout the world, including his work at the Almeida Festival in London and the Holland Festival. Mikhashoff co-founded the North American New Music Festival in 1983 with Jan Williams and remained a co-director until his death. He commissioned works from such notable composers as John Cage, Lukas Foss, Otto Luening, Poul Ruders, James Sellars, Christian Wolff, and many others. One of his most notable commissioning projects occurred in 1982 when he commissioned or solicited new tangos for solo piano from an international array of more than 80 composers. Mikhashoff also edited publications of music, including works by Henry Cowell, Lejaren Hiller, Conlon Nancarrow, and Virgil Thomson. He recorded on the New Albion, Mode, RCA Victor, CRI, and Spectrum record labels. Yvar Mikhashoff's support of contemporary music continues today through the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music which was created by his estate to support composers and performers of new music.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains 249 cassettes featuring performances either by Mikhashoff or of his music, 801 non-commercial cassettes and 115 commercially-released cassettes that do not contain performances or works by Mikhashoff. The contents represent a portrait of Mikhashoff's career, not only as pianist and composer, but also as a concert programmer. He had great enthusiasm for exploring different musical themes, including tangos, waltzes, and various eras and styles. This collection contains many examples of Mikhashoff's own spoken word descriptions of the music he was performing.
The container list descriptions are based on the original inventory, which presumably relied upon external sources such as container labels, not auditioning. Reformatting the tapes reveals many details that were previously not known, such as spoken word introductions, changes in program contents, and even blank tapes. The reformatted digital files are listed for tapes in Series I to provide some indication of how the files may match the listed contents. The cassettes that do not feature Mikhashoff have not been inventoried here but links have been provided to digital images of the cassette container spines.
Arrangement
The collection is in three series:
I. Cassettes with Mikhashoff as performer or composer
II. Non-commercial cassettes without Mikhashoff as performer or composer
III. Commercial cassettes without Mikhashoff as performer or composer
Container List
- Cassettes with Mikhashoff as performer or composer, 1967-1993, I.; Item 1-149
  Contains cassette recordings of live performances, although it is not clear if the cassettes are original recordings or duplicates from other sources. The performances date back to Mikhashoff's days as a graduate student in Texas and capture his performances from international venues, including Argentina, Denmark, Sweden, England, Germany, Italy, Hong Kong, Norway, The Netherlands, Japan, New York City, and Buffalo.
  In order as previously processed.
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 1, 16 June 1973, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Abendmusik 1973 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Isabella Lipschutz, Diane Tobola, sopranos; Amy Winn, flute; David Herbert, oboe; Cambiata Soloists Recording location: Trinity University, Ruth Taylor Music Center, San Antonio, Texas 8 works, 8 files Derivative files created: 8 (Box 1, Item 1)
    Contents: Dvorák: Moravian duets; Vivaldi: Motteto O qui coeli terrae; Mussorgsky: Three songs; Schumann: Duets; Hindemith: Song for St. Martin's day; Ravel: Five Greek folk songs; Falla: Popular Spanish songs; Ives: Four songs
    Digitized copies:
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_001_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_001_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_02-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_02-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_001_02-04pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_001_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_02-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_02-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_001_02-04sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 2, 7 December 1984, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: A-Knox: Dine Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Robert Black, contrabass; Michael Femiano, percussion; Thomas Halpin, violin; James Pyne, clarinet; Steven Rosenthal, saxophone; Ronald Vogan, trumpet; Jan Williams, percussion Recording location: Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.) Dolby; no content on Side B? Annotated: "Sahl on tape #2". From a program titled Five themes: a musical commentary for Jim Dine. Remainder of the program: Druckman: Valentine; Sahl: The exiles café 4 works, 4 files Derivative files created: 4 (Box 1, Item 2)
    Contents: Satie: Five grimaces for a Midsummer night's dream; Poulenc: Sonata for violin. Intermezzo; Dave Smith: Wallydrag rock; Druckman: Valentine
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_002_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_002_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_002_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_002_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_002_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_002_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_002_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_002_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_002_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_002_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 3, 22 January 1989, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: A-Knox: Jan 88 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; unidentified soprano Recording location: Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.) Dolby B Possible program title Transformations and landscapes Requires checking to identify content of 13 files Derivative files created: 13 (Box 1, Item 3)
    Contents: Thomson: Preciosilla; Hohvaness: Visionary landscapes no. 3 (Evening bell), no.4; Brahms: Feldeinsamket (op.86/2; Ives: Feldeinsamkeit; Beach: The year's at the spring; Rorem: Pippa's song; and more
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_003_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02am.wav
    ubmu0001_6_003_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_003_02-09pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_003_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_003_02-10sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 4, 9 June 1988, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Almeida: Feldman 1. Side A: For Morton Feldman; Side B: Introduction to several themes, Almeida Ensemble Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Almeida Ensemble Recording location: Almeida Festival (London, England) Dolby C With spoken introductions to each piece by Mikhashoff; Another portion of the concert is on Tape 5. Side B recorded 10 June 1988, performed by the Almeida Ensemble Requires checking - file 1 is spoken intro; 2nd file is Monk 3rd file is Riegger spoken intros appear at end of files, not beginnings Derivative files created: 6 (Box 1, Item 4)
    Contents: Barbara Monk Feldman: The I and Thou; Wallingford Riegger: Blue voyage; Feldman: Piano piece (1952); Nils Vigeland: Mnemosyne; Feldman: Instruments 1
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_004_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_004_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_004_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_004_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_004_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_004_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_004_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_004_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_004_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 5, 9 June 1988, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Almeida: Feldman 2. Side A: For Morton Feldman; Side B: Introduction to several themes Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Almeida Ensemble Recording location: Almeida Festival (London, England) Dolby B With spoken introductions to each piece by Mikhashoff; Another portion of the concert is on Tape 4; file 1 - spoken intro; Derivative files created: 6 (Box 1, Item 5)
    Contents: Scriabin: Piano sonata 9; Cage: Souvenir; Feldman: Piano (1977)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_005_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_005_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_005_02-02pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_005_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_005_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_005_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_005_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_005_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_005_02-02sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 6, 8 March 1983, 1 60 minute cassette; Container title: Americans in Paris Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Hall Dolby B Includes spoken introductions by Mikhashoff; check if Auric work is present Derivative files created: 17 (Box 1, Item 6)
    Contents: Gottschalk: Souvenir de la Havane; Vieuxtemps: Souvenir d'Amerique; Debussy: Minstrels; Auric: Adieu, New York; Copland: Two Preludes; Gershwin: Short story; Blake: Capricious Harlem; Copland: Slow dance and jazzy mood; Villa-Lobos: Song of the black swan; Thomson: Four portraits -- Portrait of Picasso -- Three portraits -- Fanfare for France; Spoken introduction to Antheil Sonata no.1 but not the work itself
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_006_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02am.wav
    ubmu0001_6_006_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-06pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-07pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-08pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-09pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-10pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_01-11pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-05pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_006_02-06pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_006_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-06sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-07sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-08sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-09sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-10sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_01-11sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-05sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_006_02-06sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 7, 24 November 1988, 1 60 minute cassette; Container title: Arditti + YM: Rome Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Arditti Quartet Recording location: Rome (Italy) Performed at the 25th Nuova consonanza festival Very poor audio quality Derivative files created: 3 (Box 1, Item 7)
    Contents: Sbordoni; Eros Daedalus; Ives: Set of 5 pieces for piano quintet; Mahler: Piano quartet
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_007_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_007_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_007_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_007_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_007_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_007_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_007_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_007_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 8, 22 February 1982, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Austin, TX 2-21-82 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano Recording location: University of Texas at Austin Could not check due to binding Spine date and labels on cassette do not match. The recital for Feb. 21 1982 was by the Cambiata soloists titled Mad madrigals and wintry winds 6 files, 6 groups (waltzes as 1 file) Derivative files created: 6 (Box 1, Item 8)
    Contents: Wolff: Preludes; Scelsi: Four illustrations; 12 waltzes by Glass, Babbitt, Fennimore, Moran, Wuorinen, Harrison, Stout, Finney, Feliciano, Constanten, Cage, Thomson; Sellars: Sonata no.2; Rudhyar: Rite of transcendance; Rzewski: Piano piece no.4
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_008_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_008_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_02-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_008_02-03pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_008_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_008_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_008_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_008_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_008_02-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_008_02-03sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 9, 2 September 1990, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: BBC Ruders + Janáçek Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Spectrum, Guy Protheroe, conductor Recording location: BBC (London, England) Preceded by some unrelated content then BBC announcer. Date from broadcast. Performances of the Ruders and Janacek also took place 20 November 1984. Re-do for spoken content Derivative files created: 5 (Box 1, Item 9)
    Contents: Stravinsky: Octet; Ruders: Break dance for piano and brass quintet; Janáçek: Capriccio
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_009_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_009_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_009_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_009_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_009_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_009_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_009_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_009_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_009_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_009_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_009_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_009_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 10, 4 April 1990, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: BPO: Vigeland, Felder Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, Michael Udow, percussion; Indiana University New Music Ensemble; Sollberger, conductor Recording location: North American New Music Festival 1990 (Cleveland, Ohio) 2 files, 2 works Derivative files created: 2 (Box 1, Item 10)
    Contents: Vigeland: In black and white; Felder: Between -- Journal
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_010_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_010_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_010_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_010_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_010_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_010_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 11, 30 May 1987, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: BPO: Takemitsu Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra Recording location: Buffalo (N.Y.) 4 files, 3 works: the Corigliano is split into two files Derivative files created: 4 (Box 1, Item 11)
    Contents: Ives: Ragtime Dancer; Takemitsu: Riverrun; Corigliano: Three hallucinations for orchestra (from movie Altered states)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_011_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_011_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_011_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_011_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_011_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_011_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_011_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_011_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_011_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_011_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 12, 20 April 1989, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: BPO: Smalley Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra; Jesse Levine, conductor Recording location: WBFO (Radio station: Buffalo, N.Y.) Annotated: "WBFO-FM, National Public Radio from UB". Part of North American New Music Festival. Derivative files created: 3 (Box 1, Item 12)
    Contents: Smalley: Concerto for piano and orchestra -- excerpt from unknown doublebass work -- Unknown work for saxophone quartet
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_012_01am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_012_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_012_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_012_01-03pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_012_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_012_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_012_01-03sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 13, 18 March 1978, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Baird Cont. Ensemble: Tractors and Tangos Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Baird Contemporary Ensemble Recording location: University at Buffalo 5 files, 5 works Derivative files created: 5 (Box 1, Item 13)
    Contents: Revueltas: Ocho por radio; Eisler: Palmstrom; Walton: Excerpts from Façade; Roussel: Jazz dans la nuit, op. 38; Milhaud: Farm Machinery
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_013_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_013_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_013_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_013_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_013_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_013_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_013_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_013_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_013_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_013_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_013_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_013_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 14, 13 May 1977, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Baird Contemporary Ensemble 5-13-77 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Baird Contemporary Ensemble Recording location: University at Buffalo 6 files, 4 works listed; spoken content after works Derivative files created: 6 (Box 1, Item 14)
    Contents: Cowell: Ostinato pianissimo; Mikhashoff: In memoriam Benjamin Britten; Messiaen: Colors of the celestial city; Riley: Blox; Foss: Time cycle
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_014_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_014_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_01-03pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_01-04pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_02-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_014_02-02pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_014_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_014_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_014_01-03sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_014_01-04sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_014_02-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_014_02-02sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 15, 1981, 1 60 minute cassette; Container title: Barlow Performers: de Sardikhashoff, Clementi Trio Cologne, Ensemble Köln, R. H. P. Platz; F. M. Uitti, sampled and Atari/EMAX Recording location: Darmstadt (Germany) Dolby B Sardikhashoff might be an alias for Mikhashoff 2 files, 2 works Derivative files created: 2 (Box 1, Item 15)
    Contents: Wryter: Spright the diner; Ungheresi: Im Januar am Nil
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_015_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_015_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_015_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_015_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_015_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_015_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 16, undated, 1 60 minute cassette; Container title: Berio + Friends, with Oppens (Osborne + Hachimura) Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Ken Ishii, cello; Ursula Oppens Recording location: Unknown location 3 files, 3 works Derivative files created: 3 (Box 1, Item 16)
    Contents: Berio: Linea; Osborne: Remembering Yessenin; Hachimura: Constellations
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_016_01am.wav, ubmu0001_6_016_02am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_016_01-01pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_016_01-02pm.wav, ubmu0001_6_016_02-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_016_01-01sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_016_01-02sc.mp3, ubmu0001_6_016_02-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 17, 16 April 1985, 1 60 minute cassette; Container title: Biscardi pf. cto.: 4-16-85 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Alan Heatherington, conductor; University at Buffalo Philharmonia Recording location: North American New Music Festival (Buffalo, N.Y.) Dolby B World premiere match Derivative files created: 1 (Box 1, Item 17)
    Contents: Biscardi: Piano concerto (1983)
    Preservation archival master file(s): ubmu0001_6_017_01am.wav
    Production master files: ubmu0001_6_017_01-01pm.wav
    Service copy files: ubmu0001_6_017_01-01sc.mp3
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, Tape 18, 28 January 1980, 1 90 minute cassette; Container title: Bon-bon filled... Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Concert titled A bonbon filled with snow: music of Grieg and Debussy Match Derivative files created: 11 (Box 1, Item 18)